They took a bite out of crime.
Small Time Crooks is a comedy, crime film directed by Woody Allen.
A loser of a crook and his wife strike it rich when a botched bank
job's cover business becomes a spectacular success.
Ray, played by Woody Allen.
Frenchy, played by Tracey Ullman.
Denny, played by Michael Rapaport.
Tommy, played by Tony Darrow.
Benny, played by Jon Lovitz.
David, played by Hugh Grant.
Small Time Crooks is a 2000 American crime-comedy film
written and directed by Woody Allen.
It stars Allen, Hugh Grant, Elaine May and Tracey Ullman.
The picture's plot has some similarities to that
of the 1942 comedy Larceny, Inc.
Small Time Crooks was the highest-grossing film directed by Allen at the North American
box office between 1989's Crimes and Misdemeanors and 2005's Match Point.
The film was released by DreamWorks Pictures on May 19, 2000 and received positive reviews
from critics while grossing $29.9 million against a $25 million budget.
Allen has never said whether the film's similarity to Larceny, Inc.
was deliberate or if his film was in any way inspired by it.
The plot also parallels episodes of at least two American TV series:
Gomer Pyle ("Dynamite Diner") and Car 54, Where Are You?
("The White Elephant").
The film explores themes of wife, bank, bank robber, restaurant, pizzeria.
The tone is lighthearted.